Now it's time for the important part.
The crash animation.
Because if our crash doesn't look like a really epic, our players won't understand why the trees are
to be avoided.
So let's have a look at how we can enhance this game with a nice animation.
Let's get to it.
So moving over to our player sprite, we can add in this when I receive player crashed broadcast.
So basically what we want to happen is for our player sprite to have a spin out effect when they touch
a tree.
And quite simply, all we need to do is go to the motions group and bring in this turn effect.
Then we can just repeat this say five times and giving this a go.
Skipping along until we hit a tree.
Ah well, that didn't quite work.
As you can see, it tries to turn, but it just turns back.
And also, even after we crashed, we can still ski left and right.
So let's see if we can fix that.
Well, if you look closely, you will see that the problem is caused by this script here.
And to fix this problem is quite simple.
Basically, just like we did with the tree sprite, what we need to do is stop the other scripts.
So grabbing a stop, all we can change it to stop other scripts in the sprite.
And this time, instead of putting it at the end of the script, we can add it to the start of the script.
So again, giving that a play, you will see how much better that works.
Now we have a pretty nice animation that works when we crash, but I still think we can do better.
So if you look down at our script, you can see that we turn by 15 degrees, which is fine and all,
but it does not look exactly smooth.
So I'm going to do something a little sneaky here.
And instead of 15 I'm going to turn by movement speed.
Yes, I know this seems weird, but as you will see, it works when we give this a play.
Notice how much better that animation is.
Now, the final thing to improve this even more is replace this repeat five times with a repeat until
block.
Now, just like we did with our other script, we can repeat until movement speed equals zero.
So just grab this equals block and this variable and set this to zero like that.
So giving that another go crashing into another tree.
Well, I think the results speak for themselves.
Net looks like a remarkable crash.